Misato: Are you ready Shinji?
Shinji: Um yeah.
Misato: Final safety locks, release!
Misato: Evangelion Unit-01, move out!
Ritsuko: Shinji, just oncentrate on walking for now.
Ritsuko: Uh. Walk.
Ritsuko: He's walking!
Shinji: Walking.
Misato: Shiji! Are you okay?
Misato: Hurry! Hurry!
Misato: You've got to get out!
Shinji: Oh!
Shinji: Oh! Ohhh.
Misato: Shinji, calm down! That's not your real arm!
Ritsuko: Where is defense system?
Makoto: The signal's not working!
Makoto: His field's not up! It's not unfolding!
Ritsuko: It's not up?
Ibuki: Left arm damaged!
Makoto: The circuits are snapped!
Misato: Shinji, move!
Shinji: Whoa! Ahh!
Ibuki: There's a crack on the front of the brain cases.
Ritsuko: That armor won't take much more.
Makoto: The head is damaged, extended damage, unknown!
Ibuki: The controllers are breaking up.
Aoba: We're not getting any ratings on the pilot.
Misato: No, Shiji!
Shinji: Ah!
Ibuki: Cicadas Droning
Ritsuko: Unfamiliar ceiling.
US Representative Green: So, the angels have returned.
US Representative Green: It's rather sudden.
Male Voice: It's the same as it was 15 years ago.
Male Voice: That's the way of disasters.
Male Voice: They come without warning.
UK Representative Red: On the positive side, our previous investments would appear to be not such a waste after all.
Russia Representative Purple: You can't be sure about that yet.
Russia Representative Purple: If it doesn't pay off, it's still a waste.
French Representative Yellow: Correct.
French Representative Yellow: Now that news of the Angels has become common knowledge,
French Representative Yellow: Nerve must take steps to control the manner in which this information is received by the general public.
Gendo: You may rest assured that it's already been taken care of.
Gendo: Don't worry.
Gendo: Government officials have announced that
Gendo: This incident
Misato: Public scenario B-22.
Misato: Just like we thought.
Misato: So we're covering up the truth again?
Ritsuko: Well, at least the PR people are happy.
Ritsuko: They finally got something to do.
Misato: We're being pretty casual about it.
Misato: I don't think so.
Misato: Actually, I think we're all pretty scared.
Shinji: Of course we are.
Russia Representative Purple: Well, we must acknowledge that.
US Representative Green: But still, I wonder, Mr. Ikari, were Nerve and Eva used efficiently?
French Representative Yellow: Repair costs for Unit-01 added to the development costs for Unit-00 are simply staggering.
UK Representative Red: We also understand that you gave that toy to your own son.
Russia Representative Purple: Time, money, and manpower.
Russia Representative Purple: How much more will be wasted by you and your family?
UK Representative Red: And that is not your only responsibility.
UK Representative Red: The Human Enhancement Project. That should be your top priority.
French Representative Yellow: Correct. Under these desperate circumstances, that project may be the only real hope for the future of mankind. Do you understand?
Keel Lorenz: In any event, the Angels are no excuse for the delay in the schedule of that project.
Keel Lorenz: We may consider adjusting the budget.
US Representative Green: The rest of the meeting does not concern you.
French Representative Yellow: Your presence here was... appreciated.
Keel Lorenz: Ikari, you do know that there can be no turning back.
Gendo: I know.
Gendo: Mankind has no time left.
US Representative Green: Man, air conditioning's the greatest thing.
US Representative Green: Man's Triumph over nature!
Ritsuko: Shinji's finally woken up!
Misato: And... how is he?
Ritsuko: Well, his memory seems a bit muddled, but...
Misato: You don't think it could be contamination, do you?
Ritsuko: I don't think we should worry.
Misato: Really?
Misato: You're right. He did have a pretty hectic day.
Ritsuko: Poor little kid. His cerebellum must have taken a lot of stress.
Misato: Cerebellum? Don't you mean his heart?
Misato: If Eva and this city both operated their full potential, we might make it through this.
Ritsuko: You're such an optimist.
Misato: Hey, sometimes you need a little wishful thinking just to keep on living.
Ritsuko: I see your point. It's nice to hear a positive attitude. I'll see you later.
Misato: Okay, see ya.
Female Voice: Dr. Uga'i, Internal Department 1. Dr. Uga'i, Internal Department 1.
Female Voice: Please call Dr. Azuma of the First Surgical Department immediately.
Female Voice: The medical conference regarding the B experiment will be held as scheduled.
Female Voice: All supervisors, please proceed to conference room two.
Ritsuko: They don't want to live together? Are you sure?
Fuyutski: I think that living apart is natural to them.
Ritsuko: And being together is unnatural?
Misato: You'll be living alone?
Male Voice: That's right. His room will be on the sixth block beyond this one. Is that alright?
Shinji: Yes, sir.
Misato: Shinji, are you sure about that?
Shinji: Living alone is fine with me. I'm alone anyway.
Ritsuko: What did you say?
Misato: You heard me! I said I'll be taking Shinji home to live in my place, okay?
Misato: It's already been approved.
Misato: And don't worry, I'm not gonna be making any passes at him.
Ritsuko: Of course you're not! How could you even think of such a thing?
Ritsuko: You've got no shame at all!
Misato: Some people don't have any sense of humor.
Misato: Well, I guess we have to have a party tonight, huh?
Shinji: Why is that?
Shinji: It's a welcoming party in honor of my new roommate, of course
Female Voice: Yes, I'd never have dreamt that this city would become a battlefield
Woman 2: Yeah, my husband's saying that at least the kids and I should move.
Female Voice: Don't I know it
Female Voice: This city may be a fortress, but that's no guarantee of safety.
Woman 2: Just thinking about last night gives me the chills.
Misato: I hope you don't mind if we make a little stop on the way.
Shinji: A stop where?
US Representative Green: Oh, it's a really cool place.
Shinji: It's so desolate.
Shinji: The city seems so lonely.
Misato: Here we go.
Shinji: It's awesome.
Shinji: The buildings are growing!
Misato: This city is a fortress designed to stand against the angels.
Misato: This is Tokyo 3.
Misato: This is our city, and it's the city that you saved.
Misato: Your things out to have been delivered already shinji.
Misato: Hey, come in.
Shinji: I don't want to intrude.
Misato: Shinji, this is *your* home now.
Shinji: Uh. I'm...I'm home.
Misato: Welcome home.
Misato: Um, as you can see, the place is just a little bit messy, but ahah go ahead and make yourself comfortable.
Shinji: Um, This is a *little* messy?
Misato: Oh, sorry. Could you put the food in the fridge, please?
Shinji: Uh, yes, ma'am.
Shinji: Ice, snacks, and 50 gallons of beer.
Shinji: What kind of life does she lead?
Shinji: Huh.
Shinji: Uh, excuse me. What's in the other fridge?
Misato: Oh, don't mind that. He's probably still sleeping.
Shinji: Sleeping?
Misato: Let's eat!
Shinji: Yeah, let's eat.
Misato: Woo! Yeah! Good stuff! Uhp.
Misato: You know, life just doesn't get any better than this.
Misato: Hmm? Not hungry? It's good, even if it is all instant.
Shinji: I-I'm sorry. I'm just not used to food like this.
Misato: WHAT? Are you finicky?
Misato: HM?
Shinji: Um, no. That's not what... Uh, well.
Misato: Isn't this nice?
Misato: Having two for dinner sure beats eating alone, ?
Shinji: Uh huh?
Misato: Here we go. Let's go for the next one.
Misato: Paper, scissors, stone.
Misato: Three, two, one, go!
Misato: I'm sorry, Shinji.
Misato: Okay, that was a really fair way to split up the chores, wasn't it?
Shinji: Yeah.
Misato: This is your home, so feel free to take advantage of everything here.
Misato: Except, of course, of me, that is.
US Representative Green: Uh, yes, ma'am.
Misato: Hoo. Yes, yes, yes.
Misato: Is that all you can say?
Misato: It's *getting* on my nerves!
Misato: You're a bully! Act like one!
Shinji: Yes, ma'am!
Misato: I guess that's just the way you are.
Misato: Why don't you go take a bath?
Misato: Yeah! Wash away your troubles!
Misato: Bathing cleans the mind and soul.
Shinji: Ohoh.
Shinji: Oh! Miss Misano! Uh pp, uh pp.
Misato: What?
Misato: Oh, him?
Misato: He's one of those new warm water penguins.
Shinji: Uhuh, That was... that was a wa-what?
Misato: His name's Penpen. He's your other roommate.
Misato: Why don't you cover up?
Shinji: Ohuh?
Misato: Huh. I guess I should be nicer, but he's probably already made up his mind about me.
Shinji: Misato Katsaragi.
Shinji: She's not a bad person.
Misato: Bathing claims the mind and soul!
Shinji: But bad memories always seem to find me in the bath.
Shinji: Like my father.
Shinji: And that girl Rei.
Ritsuko: So how was Rei today?
Ritsuko: You did see her at the hospital today, didn't you?
Gendo: She can work again in 20 days.
Gendo: By then, we'll be ready to reactivate Unit-00 from cryostasis.
Ritsuko: It's so hard on these children.
Gendo: There's no one else who can pilot the Evas.
Gendo: As long as they survive, that is what I'll have them do.
Ritsuko: With no regard to what *they* may want?
Misato: Yeahuh, after all the horrible stuff he went through, I don't think he'll pilot again.
Ritsuko: Maintaining him is part of your job.
Misato: I'm just scared.
Misato: I don't know how to deal with him.
Ritsuko: Grumbling already?
Ritsuko: But it was your idea to take him in, you know.
Misato: Oh, shut up!
Misato: Huh, I was just thinking of Shinji as a tool.
Misato: I'm as shameless as Ritsuko.
Misato: We destroyed the angel, but...
Misato: I don't feel happy.
Shinji: Another unfamiliar ceiling.
Shinji: Of course, in this whole city, there's no place that's familiar.
Misato: This is *your* home now.
Shinji: Why am I here?
Makoto: The head is damaged. The head is damaged!
Ibuki: We're having problems maintaing activation!
Misato: Status report!
Ibuki: Syncrograph reversing.
Ibuki: The pulses are blowing backwards!
Ritsuko: Break the circuit now!
Ritsuko: Do it!
Ibuki: We can't!
Ibuki: It's not accepting the signal!
Misato: What about Shinji?
Makoto: His monitors aren't reacting.
Makoto: His condition's unknown!
Aoba: Unit 1's gone completely silent!
Ritsuko: Misato!
Misato: We've got no choice.
Misato: Abort the operation!
Misato: We've got to rescue the pilot!
Misato: Eject the entry plug!
Ibuki: We can't!
Ibuki: It's completely out of control!
Misato: *What* did you say?
Misato: The Eva's reactivating.
Ibuki: I don't believe it! This can't be!
Misato: My god!
Ritsuko: Berserker.
Fuyutski: We've done it.
Ritsuko: It's an AT field!
Misato: No, not now! As long as that field is up!
Ritsuko: He can't get near that angel!
Aoba: The left arm's regenerated itself!
Misato: - No way!
Ibuki: Unit-01's expanding its own AT field!
Ibuki: It's neutralizing the phase space!
Ritsuko: No! It's breaking through it!
Misato: It went through the AT field like it wasn't there!
Misato: It's gonna self destruct!
Misato: Whoa!
Misato: Is the Eva?!
US Representative Green: Whoah!
Ritsuko: That must be,
Misato: Eva's true form.
Makoto: Circuits reconnected.
Ibuki: Systems restored.
Ibuki: Graphs back to normal.
Makoto: Pilot life science confirmed.
Misato: Preserving the pilot's life is our first priority.
Ritsuko: Send out the recovery team.
Ritsuko: Hurry!
Shinji: Huh? Huh? Uh. Uhuh! Oh. Ohh. Huh. AHH!
Misato: Shinji, can I come in?
Misato: I forgot to tell you something.
Misato: You did something *very* good and *very* noble today.
Misato: You should, be proud.
Misato: Good night, Shinji.
Misato: Hang in there.
Claire Littley: Claire Littley: Fly me to the moon and let me play among the stars
Claire Littley: Let me see what spring is like on Jupiter and Mars
Claire Littley: In other words, hold my hand
Claire Littley: In other words, don't end kiss me
Claire Littley: Fill my heart with some
Claire Littley: And let me sing forevermore
Claire Littley: You are all I long for
Claire Littley: All I worship and adore
Claire Littley: In other words
Claire Littley: Please be true
Claire Littley: In all the words
Claire Littley: I love you
Misato: Shinji's life is busier than ever, but he keeps to himself, friendless, until it's revealed that he's an Eva pilot.
Misato: However, this new hero status brings both embarrassment and the wrath of one boy in particular.
Misato: Don't miss the next episode, and I'll sneak in a little bonus, okay?